# **BRETT SAIKI**

Graduate Student ~ Research Assistant

😯 bsaiki.com

bksaiki

bksaiki@gmail.com

**in** brett.saiki

### **SUMMARY**

Graduate student doing research in programming languages, computer number systems, and term rewriting; obsessed with all things floating-point in both software and hardware.

**Languages:** C, C++, Racket, Rust, Java, Python **Interests:** Programming Languages, Floatin

Programming Languages, Floatingpoint, Numerics, Verification

EDUCATION

**University of Washington** | *Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science and Engineering* M.S. Computer Science and Engineering

Sep. 2023 — Present Seattle, WA

**University of Washington** | *Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science and Engineering* B.S. Computer Engineering, B.A. Mathematics

Aug. 2019 — Jun. 2023 Seattle, WA

**EXPERIENCE** 

## University of Washington | Seattle, WA

Sep. 2023 — Present

Research Assistant

- · developing tools and libraries for floating-point accuracy optimization and term rewriting
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  collaborating with undergraduate students, graduate students, and professors

Intel Corporation | Folsom, CA

Jun. 2023 — Sep. 2023

Mathematical Hardware Intern

Jun. 2022 — Sep. 2022

- developed compilers for translating numerical specifications, libraries for formally verifying hardware designs, and visualization tools for simulating numerical algorithms
- · improved high-level graphics hardware algorithms

### University of Washington | Seattle, WA

Sep. 2022 — Jun. 2023

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Dec. 2019 — Jun. 2022

- · developed tools and libraries for floating-point accuracy optimization and term rewriting
- · collaborated with graduate students, professors, and industrial groups

# University Enterprises Inc. | Santa Ana, CA

Jun. 2019 — Aug. 2019

Contracted by State Compensation Insurance Fund (SCIF)

Summer Intern

- · learned lifecycle of a worker's compensation insurance claim
- indexed digital documents, digitized physical claims, contacted medical providers for work status updates

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Equality Saturation Theory Exploration à la Carte**

Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages and Applications (OOPSLA) 2023

Anjali Pal, Brett Saiki, Ryan Tjoa, Cynthia Richey, Amy Zhu, Oliver Flatt, Max Willsey, Zachary Tatlock, Chandrakana Nandi

# Odyssey: An Interactive Workbench for Expert-Driven Floating-Point Expression Rewriting

ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST) 2023

Edward Misback, Caleb C. Chan, Brett Saiki, Eunice Jun, Zachary Tatlock, Pavel Panchekha

### Rewrite Rule Inference Using Equality Saturation | Distinguished Paper Award

Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages and Applications (OOPSLA) 2021

Chandrakana Nandi, Max Willsey, Amy Zhu, Brett Saiki, Yisu Wang, Adam Anderson, Adriana Schulz, Dan Grossman, Zachary Tatlock

## **Combining Precision Tuning and Rewriting**

IEEE International Symposium on Computer Arithmetic (ARITH) 2021

Brett Saiki, Oliver Flatt, Chandrakana Nandi, Pavel Panchekha, Zachary Tatlock

RESEARCH

FPBench | Project

Herbie | Project

Ruler | Project

FPCore tools, compilers, benchmarks *NSV 2016* 

Floating-point accuracy improver *PLDI 2015, ARITH 2021, UIST 2023* 

Rewrite rule synthesizer for equalitysaturation applications OOPSLA 2021, OOPSLA 2023

**PROJECTS** 

**Minim** | Project Scheme interpreter written in C mpmfnum | Project | Docs Number systems library in Rust **generic-flonum** | Project | Docs Alternate MPFR interface in Racket with subnormalization and exponent bounds